# Hi, I'm **Julian Lo**

## l design, develop, maintain and test apps

My GitHub My Facebook My LinkedIn My Yelp Email Me c. 425-894-1133

## Objective

I'm a UI developer — at Microsoft for 8 years — transitioning into mobile, full-stack, and open-sourced development. My strongest interest lies in building beautiful and delightful user experiences on mobile devices. My current focus has been on Android app development, and have been learning iOS development as well.

#### Skill Set

Android/Android Studio, Java, Node.js/Express, Mongo, Amazon EC2 (1 year) iOS, Electron, React Native, Firebase (Learning + strong interest, <1 year) C++, C++/CX, COM, Win32 (7 years) C#/.NET, XAML, Windows Runtime (2 years)

#### **Employment History**

#### Senior Android Engineer (Contract) | Avanti Markets app BYNDL | 2016

Worked 3 month contract to implement version 2 of the Avanti Markets app.

- Implemented complete UX redesign and released to Google Play Store.
- Implemented layout optimizations for phone and tablet form factors.
- Designed and implemented tool to allow the app to be re-themed with new colour scheme and app logos.
- Tech: Android, Java, Electron, JavaScript

### Senior Software Engineer | <u>Windows Spotlight</u> (Windows 10) Microsoft | 2013 - 2015

- Ideated, prototyped, and implemented UX for Windows Spotlight.
- Implemented XAML custom controls ("hotspot controls") used to subtly reveal information to the user and also collect feedback from the user.
- Mentored/led two junior developers also working on the feature.
- Tech: C++/CX, XAML, COM, Windows Runtime

#### Software Engineer II | Out Of Box Experience (Windows 8) Microsoft | 2010 - 2012

The "Out Of Box Experience" is the Windows component responsible for executing final per-machine setup/provisioning tasks that must occur after the OS is installed but before the user starts using the machine.

- Worked on a plugin-based task execution engine for completing critical machine provisioning tasks.
- Wrote modern Windows 8-style wizard and wizard pages.
- Tech: C++, COM, Windows Runtime

### Software Engineer | HomeGroup UX (Windows 7) Microsoft | 2007 - 2010

HomeGroup was a feature introduced in Windows 7 allowing users on a single subnet (i.e. a home) to easily share files with each other.

- Wrote wizard and control panel pages to allow users to configure their HomeGroup and network settings.
- (Tech: C++, COM, Win32)

### Side Projects

# Pics for reddit - Android app 2016

The app is a Reddit client, specifically for viewing image posts from Reddit.

- Key features include proper user token management, infinite scrolling lists, pleasant animations and transitions.
- Relevant links: <u>Google Play Store</u>, <u>GitHub</u>

# Bathroom Maps - Android app, Node.js server 2015 - 2016

This app that helps locate public bathrooms, and allows users to suggest new bathrooms and write reviews for existing ones. (Tech: Android/Java, Node.js/Express, Mongo)

- Implemented a REST API built on Node.js to retrieve, review, and manage the list of bathrooms.
- Used Mongo DB and geospatial indexing for fast retrieval of bathrooms by geolocation.
- Built an Android app to view and review the bathrooms, caching data appropriately and allowing bathrooms to be filtered by category and rating.
- GitHub links: Android, Server. (Google Play Store release pending)

#### Picture Bible - Android app 2015

My first crack at an Android app. Picture Bible is a fun bible app that displays photos of architecture, food, nature, and animals behind each chapter. (Links: <u>Google Play Store</u>, <u>GitHub</u>)

#### Education

## University of Waterloo - Bachelor of Mathematics

#### 2002 - 2007

- Majored in Computer Science, minored in Pure Mathematics
- Cumulative GPA of 85%

#### References

Available on request